http://www.policeone.com/info/privacy/

Privacy Policy
Make Police1 your homepage
Open the tools menu in your browser. This may be called “Tools” or use an icon like the cog
or menu bars
Select the option or tab named “Internet Options (Internet Explorer)”, “Options (Firefox)”, “Preferences (Safari)” or “Settings (Chrome)”.
Look for a box or option labeled “Home Page (Internet Explorer, Firefox, Safari)” or “On Startup (Chrome)”.
Enter “https://www.police1.com/” and click OK.
If you need further help setting your homepage, check your browser’s Help menu
Community Policing
Coronavirus (COVID-19)
PRIVACY POLICY
This Web site is owned and operated by:
Lexipol
2611 Internet Blvd., Ste. 100
Frisco, TX 75034
We are committed to maintaining your confidence and trust with respect to the information we collect from you. This privacy policy applies to www.PoliceOne.com (“Police1”) sets forth what information we collect about you, how we use your information, and the choices you have about how we use your information.
Police1 is dedicated to safeguarding your privacy online. As a policy, we will not sell or otherwise misuse your personal information. Your personal information helps us customize Police1 to your interests and allows us to negotiate valuable member discounts and related services. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our many offerings.
This privacy policy was last updated on 04/27/2018
What personal information does Police1 collect from me?
Police1 collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of web sites.
Some personal information is gathered when you register. During registration, Police1 asks all users for your name, date of birth, email address, city, occupation, department information, industry and personal interests.  Once you register you are no longer anonymous to Police1 - you will select an appropriate Police1 username and then given access to Police1's many offerings.
In addition to registration we may ask you for personal information (such as the above) at other times, including (but not limited to) when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by Police1 and/or our many partners; when you post a Police1 Classified ad; when you submit a listing for a web site; and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. If you contact Police1 we may keep a record of that correspondence. Police1 also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Wherever Police1 collects personal information we include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.
What are cookies/tracking technologies and how does Police1 use them?
Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Police1 and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.
We use cookies to:
1. Remind us of whom you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie passes your username and password when you register or "Sign In" and is modified when you "Sign Out" of our services. Other submitted personal information such as occupation and city are not linked to cookies.
2. Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing Police1 is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior.
3. Track your progress and number of entries in some of our promotions, sweepstakes and contests. When a Police1-hosted promotion uses cookies, the information written to the cookie indicates the player's progress through the promotion, and may be used to track entries, submissions, and status in prize drawings.
4. Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of Police1's network of web sites you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Police1 a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites.
Advertising networks that serve ads onto Police1 may also use their own cookies.  Some of our business partners (e.g., advertisers) use cookies on our site.  We have no access to or control over these cookies.  This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by Police1.com only and does not cover the use of cookies by any of these third parties. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking here.  Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising.  You will continue to receive generic ads from our advertisers.
You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those Police1 services that require registration in order to participate.
We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 and Flash to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 and Flash to collect and store information. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies click here:
As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. Police1 also collects IP addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. In addition, Police1 Mail includes IP addresses in outgoing mail message headers. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.
Our tracking technology used to for client campaigns throughout the site does not collect any personal identifiable information that you provide as a part of your Police1 membership.  Your personal information stored in cookies is only used for the purposes listed above to help improve your user experience.
Who is collecting information?
When you are on a Police1 site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with Police1 alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. For example, some Police1 services, like BLUtube, are offered as a brand of Police1 using the same infrastructure and member database.  This information is stored within a cookie during login and not otherwise collected by a partner company for any purpose.  If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than Police1, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service.  Our privacy policy does apply to the information collected on these co-branded sites.  You should read the privacy statement of our co-branded partner. If you have any questions about the use of your information by co-branded sites or experience login problems on a co-branded site please visit the technical support section.
Promotions that run on Police1 may be sponsored by companies other than Police1 or may be cosponsored by Police1 and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared.
Please be aware that Police1 advertisers or web sites that have links on our site may collect personal information about you. The information practices of those web sites linked to Police1 are not covered by this privacy statement. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.
With whom does Police1 share my information?
As a general rule, Police1 will not disclose any of your personal information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances described below. Please see the Terms of Service or Use Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed.
Business Partners & Sponsors: Police1 may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. Details of shared use can be found in specific Terms of Service or Use Agreements, and sweepstakes and promotions rules. Some or all data collected during a Police1 promotion may be shared with a sponsor. If your personal information will be shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data.
Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give Police1 permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your email address will be shared. If more information will be shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer.
Merchants listed on Police1 have separate privacy and data collection practices. Police1 has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding the merchant, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store's home page and click on their Information link.
From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, Police1 will (with your permission) share your name and email address with them. If you wish to no longer receive materials from these third parties, please contact them directly.
Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate: Under confidentiality agreements, Police1 may match user information with third party data. Also, Police1 discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 75% of our users are male and are interested in firefighting) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.
Disclosure of Personal Information to Third Parties
Access to your personal information is restricted to our employees, agents, representatives and service providers and entities for whom we are acting as an agent, licensee or publisher, such as societies and our affiliated group companies, for the purposes set forth above. Service providers are only allowed to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.
With your consent, we also may share your personal information with our affiliated group companies and/or with non-affiliated third parties that wish to send you information about their products and services that may be of interest to you, and users who have consented to receive such information may receive communications from these third parties.
We will not otherwise disclose any personal information without your consent except under the following circumstances:
- In response to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our rights to defend against legal claims, protect your safety or the safety of others;
- If we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, safety of person or property, violation of our policies, or as otherwise required by law; and
- If Police1, a related asset or line of business is acquired by, transferred to or merged with another company, in which case, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.
What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?
Police1 may, from time to time, send you email regarding our products and services. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from Police1 and our partners, we may occasionally send you direct mail about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. Only Police1 (or agents working on behalf of Police1 and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily edit your Police1 Account Information to no longer receive such offers and mailings. You will need your Police1 ID and Password in order to access your Police1 Account Information.  To update your profile, subscription options or any other Police1 member information please visit your profile page.
On some types of Police1 promotions, we will ask for your email address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. When you participate in these types of promotions, you automatically receive promotion-related email, unless you choose the no-email option that some promotions offer. Occasionally these promotion-related email messages may include targeted advertisements.
Police1 does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will only share PII with third parties in ways that are described in this privacy policy. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests or you contact us at customersupport@PoliceOne.com.
What is Police1's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personal information?
You may edit, update or delete your Police1 Account Information and your public Police1 Profile at any time by using your Police1 ID and password. If you have forgotten your password, please click here to request a new password. For all other problems signing in to Police1, please contact us at customersupport@PoliceOne.com.
The profile you create on our site will be publically accessible unless otherwise indicated. You may change the privacy settings of your profile through your account portal.
If an account/profile was created without your knowledge/authorization, please contact us at (email) to request removal of the profile.
Your Police1 account can be deleted or deactivated, but doing so will result in not being able to access any members-only area of the Police1 network, including your Police1 Mail account (if you have one). If you saved the confirmation email you received when you first created your Police1 account, you can use the URL provided in that message to delete your account at any time. Please contact privacypolicy@PoliceOne.com for further instructions about deleting or deactivating your Police1 account.
If you are participating in a Police1 promotion and you wish to update your email address on the promotions mailing list or to quit a promotion and cease receiving promotion-related email, please contact feedback@PoliceOne.com or update the subscription settings on your personal profile. All login pages where you are required to enter your username and password are protected by industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption.
Knowing that you use certain services or features may help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. But as with all personal information, we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners regarding financial product or service usage on Police1 are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personal information about any individual user.
Data Retention
We retain the personal information we collect from you for as long as the information is relevant to our business purposes or until you request that we remove the data by contacting Lexipol below. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Unsubscribing and opting out of personal information
Your email address will only be used for us to send you materials that you have subscribed to in the past. We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personal information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. If you wish to update or remove any of your personal information please visit your profile page at anytime.
If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter or other promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the unsubscribe instructions included in each communication, by updating your profile or emailing customersupport@PoliceOne.com.
If you continue to have issues after using all the resources above, then give us a call at 866-402-4371 to talk to our Member Services Coordinator.
You will be notified when your personal information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party.
Tell a Friend
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. This feature is available with Police1 articles, tips and videos throughout Police1.com. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Police1 does not store this information and will not send any additional messages to the referred user.
What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?
Your Police1 Account Information and Police1 Profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your Police1 Account Information and Police1 Profile by using your Police1 ID and password.
We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Police1 will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Also remember to sign out of your Police1 account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe.
Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Police1 cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.
What security precautions are in place to protect the identity and security of Law Enforcement officials on Police1?
Police1 has taken several precautions to protect the identity, account names and passwords of officers when they register and log on to Police1.com. All transfer of registration and login information is encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL). Unfortunately, this process cannot be 100% secure and Police1 is not responsible for the misuse of these user names and passwords. Despite all of our precautions, you use Police1 at your own risk.
Testimonials
We periodically post member testimonials on Police1 which may contain personal information such as the member's username. We do obtain the member's consent prior to posting each testimonial. If you have any questions regarding testimonials on Police1 or would like a testimonial that includes your personal information removed please contact us.
Social Media Widgets
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.
3RD PARTY ADS
Our web site use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, Click here
Changes in this Privacy Statement
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.
We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently.  If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective.
If you ever have questions regarding the Police1 privacy policy please email customersupport@PoliceOne.com.
Police1 Top 5
Ark. LEO killed, another injured in shooting
Bodycam video shows brutal attack on LAPD officer inside station
Video: Suspect stabs officer, is fatally shot
Texas officer charged with murder in fatal store shooting
Texas sheriff charged in ‘Live PD’ case related to man’s death
More Police1 Articles
Copyright © 2020 Police1. All rights reserved.
Lexipol.
All rights reserved.
Police1 is revolutionizing the way the law enforcement community
finds relevant news, identifies important training information,
interacts online and researches product purchases
and manufacturers.
It's the most comprehensive and trusted online destination for law enforcement agencies and police departments worldwide.
Copyright © 2020
Lexipol.
All rights reserved.
Visit other Police1 Network Sites:
